daddario.com 2019-06-17

# D'Addario Strings : Privacy Policy

**D'Addario & Company, Inc.  
Privacy Policy - Your Privacy Rights**

* * *

Effective Date: 6/10/2015. Last Updated: 6/18/2018 

 **This Privacy Policy applies to the sites and apps where it appears.**   
This Policy (together with our Terms and Conditions of Use and our Tracking Tools Policy) describes how we treat information we collect from or about you on the websites and apps where it is located. This includes evansdrumheads.com, promark.com, puresoundpercussion.com, woodwinds.daddario.com, and accessories.daddario.com and their related apps. By accessing or using our websites and apps or interacting with us, you consent to these practices. 

The service providers and responsible entities with regard to the collection, processing and utilization of personal data in connection with the above websites are D'Addario & Company, 595 Smith Street, Farmingdale, New York, 11735, United States and D’Addario UK Limited, 2 Greenfinch Way, Newburn Riverside, Newcastle upon Tyne NE15 8NX, United Kingdom. For the purpose of European data protection laws, the data controllers are D'Addario & Company, Inc. and D'Addario UK Limited. 

 **We collect information from and about you.**   
**We collect contact information.** For example, we might collect your name and email address if you register on our sites or apps. We may also collect your phone number and mailing address if you make a purchase or sign up for our loyalty program. 

**We collect demographic and location information.** We may collect information like your gender and age. We may also collect your zip code or postcode. We may also collect your GPS location. We might collect this when you engage with our websites or contact us. 

**We collect payment information.** For example, we collect your credit card details if you make a purchase. 

**We collect information you submit or post.** For example, we collect product reviews and comments that you post on our site and your responses to surveys you complete. We also collect information when you contact us. 

**We collect transaction and preference data.** We collect information about your purchase history and transactions and your preferences when using our products and services.  ** **

 **We collect other behavioral and  usage information.** If you use our website, we may collect information about the browser you’re using or your IP address. We might also collect device identifiers. We might look at what site you came from, or what site you visit when you leave us. We may collect page interaction information and methods used to browse away from the page. If you use our mobile apps, we may also look at how often you use the app and where you downloaded it. We collect this information using the tracking tools described below. To control those tools, please read the Choices section below.

 **We collect information in different ways.**   
**We collect information directly from you.** For example, we collect information if you sign up for an account or sign up for our emails. We also collect information if you make a purchase or contact us. We also collect information if you post a comment, make a request or complete a survey.

 **We collect information from you passively.** We use tracking tools like browser cookies and web beacons to collect information from and about you. We collect information about users over time when you use this website. We may have third parties collect personal information this way. Learn more about these tools, how we use them and how you can control them, here. 

**We get information about you from other sources.** Third parties we work with may give us information about you. These third parties might include business partners and service providers. These third parties might also include advertising and analytics providers. Social media platforms may also give us information about you.

 **We combine information.** For example, we may combine information that we have collected offline with information we collect online. Or we may combine information we get from a third party with information we already have. 

**We use information as disclosed and described here.**   
**We use information to fulfill your orders and respond to your requests or questions.** For example, we may contact you about your loyalty account or feedback. We use your information to fulfill your purchases. We also use your information to create and administer your account.

 **We use information to improve our products and services.** We may use your information to make our website and products better. We might use your information to customize your experience with us. 

**We use information to administer our site and services and for internal operations.** This might include troubleshooting, data analysis or testing. We might also use information for research, statistical and survey purposes.

 **We use information for security purposes.** We may use information to protect our company or our third parties. These third parties may include customers or business partners.  We also may use information to protect, our websites or our services, as well as to detect and investigate activities that may be illegal or prohibited.

 **We use information for marketing purposes.** For example, we might provide you with information about special promotions or offers.  We might also use your information to serve you ads about our products and offers. We might tell you about new features or services.  These might be our own offers or products, or third-party offers or products we think you might find interesting. We may also use your data in order to build profiles and infer what advertising may be of interest to you. If you register with us, you may opt-in to receive our email newsletter. To learn about your choices for these communications, read the Choices section below. 

**We use information to communicate with you about your account or our relationship.** For example, we might send you emails about your loyalty account or feedback.  We might also contact you about our policies or our website terms. We may also use push notifications on our apps.

 **We use information as otherwise disclosed or permitted by law.**

 **We will share your information with third parties.**   
**We will share information within the D’Addario family of companies.** This includes our subsidiaries and affiliates. This also includes our brands, such as D'Addario Accessories, Evans Drumheads, Promark Drumsticks, D'Addario Woodwinds, and PureSound Percussion. We may share your information with our affiliate in order for them to communicate product offers, listings and events that we believe you might be interested in. 

**We will share your  information with third parties who perform services on our behalf.** For example, we share information with vendors who send emails for us. We also share information with companies that help us manage and operate our sites and apps or fulfill purchases. We also share information with third parties like advertisers and advertising networks that assist us in marketing and advertising our products or services. We may also share information with analytics and search engine providers. 

**We may share your information with our business partners including for marketing purposes.** For example, we might share information with third parties who co-sponsor a promotion. We might also share information with our distributors and dealers. Some of these partners may send you information about products or services by mail or email.  They may share your information with other third parties.

 **We will share your information if we think we have to in order to comply with the law or to protect ourselves, our customers and others.** For example, we may share information to respond to a court order or subpoena.  We may also share information if a government agency or investigatory body requests it. This includes sharing your information with the US government. We might also share your information in order to enforce our agreements, and to protect the rights of others. We might also share information when we are investigating potential fraud.  This might include fraud we think has happened during a promotion. If you are the winner of a sweepstakes or contest, we may also share your information with anyone who requests a winner’s list.

 **We may share your information with a successor to all or part of our business.** For example, if part of our business is sold, we may include user information as part of that transaction. We may also share your information if there is a similar change to our corporate structure. We may also share your information with others as they conduct diligence of our corporate changes.

 **We may share information for other reasons we may describe to you from time to time as permitted by law.**

 **You have certain choices about how we use your information.**   
**You can opt out of receiving our marketing emails.** To stop receiving our promotional emails, you can visit your account settings on the site or follow the instructions in any promotional message you get from us or email us at [privacypolicy@daddario.com](mailto:privacypolicy@daddario.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Request). Even if you opt out of getting messages, we will still send you transactional messages. These include responses to your questions. 

 **You can control if we share information with third parties for their marketing purposes.** To opt out of having us share your information with third parties for their promotional purposes, please send an email to [privacypolicy@daddario.com](mailto:privacypolicy@daddario.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Request). 

**You can control certain cookies and tracking tools.** To learn how to manage how we – and our vendors – use cookies and other tracking tools, please click here. 

**Your California Privacy Rights.**   
If you reside in California, you have the right to ask us one time each year if we have shared personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make a request, please send us an email, or write to us at the address listed below. Indicate in your letter that you are a California resident making a “Shine the Light” inquiry.   

**These sites are not intended for children.**   
Our sites and apps where this policy is found are meant for adults. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 without permission from a parent or guardian. If you are a parent or legal guardian and think your child under 13 has given us information, you can contact us at [privacypolicy@daddario.com](mailto:privacypolicy@daddario.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Request). You can also write to us at the address listed at the end of this Policy. Please mark your inquiries “COPPA Information Request.” Parents in the U.S. can learn more about how to protect children's privacy on-line [here](https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-privacy-online).  

 **We use standard security measures.**   
The Internet is not 100% secure. We cannot promise that your use of our sites or services will be completely safe. Any transmission of your data to our site is at your own risk. We encourage you to use caution when using the Internet. This includes not sharing your passwords. We keep personal information as long as it is necessary or relevant for the practices described in this Policy. We also keep information as otherwise required by law.  

 **We may process and store information in the United States.**   
Information we collect from you may be transferred to, processed in, or stored in the United States or another destination outside of the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”). The laws of the United States do not afford the same protection as those of the EEA.  Information may be processed by personnel operating in these locations who work for us or one of our business partners. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing and processing.  

 **You may access, delete or object in the processing of  your personal data.**   
Except as otherwise identified in this Policy, you may request that we stop, or limit, using your information. You may also request that we remove your personal information from our system or that we rectify your personal information if the personal information we have stored is incorrect or incomplete. You may also request a description of the personal information we have collected about you, or to receive a copy of your collected data. You may also request that we transfer your personal information to another company or to receive your personal information in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. 

If you have provided us with your consent to collect or use your personal information, you may withdraw your consent at any time and for any reason, without affecting the lawfulness of our processing based on your consent prior to the withdrawal. If you feel that we have violated your privacy rights, you have the right to make a complaint to us using the information listed below or to contact your local data protection authority. 

To exercise the foregoing rights, please contact us using the information listed below. Please note your right to access your personal data is not absolute. We may deny you access to your personal data when required or authorized by law. For example, we may deny access if granting access would have an unreasonable impact on another individual’s privacy.

If you are not satisfied with our response to your complaint or believe our processing of your information does not comply with data protection law, you can make a complaint to the UK Information Commissioner's Office (ICO): <https://ico.org.uk/concerns/>.  

 **We may link to third party sites or services we don’t control.**   
If you click on a link to a third party site, you will be taken to a website we do not control. This Policy does not apply to the privacy practices of that website, which may collect information from you. Read the privacy policy of other websites carefully. We are not responsible for these third party websites or their policies.

Our site may also serve third party ads or content that contains third party cookies or tracking technologies. We do not control the use of those technologies.  

 **Feel free to contact us if you have more questions.**   
If you have any questions about this Policy or want to correct or update your information, please email us at [privacypolicy@daddario.com](mailto:privacypolicy@daddario.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Request). Please do not include your credit card number or other sensitive information in your email. You can also write to us or call at: 

D'Addario & Company, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy Officer  
595 Smith Street  
Farmingdale, New York 11735  
Phone: 1 (800) 323-2746

 **We may update this Policy.**   
From time to time we may change our privacy policies. We will notify you of any material changes to our Policy as required by law. We will also post an updated copy on our website. Please check our site periodically for updates. Your continued use of our website and apps means that you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information as set out in the updated Policy.

© 2018 D'Addario & Company, Inc. All rights reserved.
